Guide to the Jack Miles papers MS.F.045
Special Collections and Archives, University of California, Irvine Libraries
- Speaking engagements, 1975-2021; Series 4.
  - The Monstrous in Biography, The Franke Lecture, Yale University (unpublished), 2006 April 18-2006 May 21 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "Israel as Foundling..." Italy trip and related material, 2005 March (Box 12, Folder 17)
    The material in this folder relates to the writings in Box 12 Folder 15 and 16.
  - "Why I Left", 2018 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - "Becoming Who I Am: Finding Truth and Community in a Diverse and Divided America", Fourth Annual "Intentional Conversation", Skirball Institute on American Values, Huntington Library (unpublished), 2002 May 22 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - A note of correction regarding Hindu Polytheism, written for the website of the Terry Gross show, circa 2014-2015 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - "What Matters to Me and Why" via Zoom to University of California, Irvine, 2021 March (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Unprocessed audiovisual material, circa 1990s (Box 19)
    Includes audiocassettes and VHS tapes.
- Fellowships and memberships, 1997-2008; Series 5.
  This series consists of material related to Miles as a Fellow or member of organizations. The material includes project proposals, a preliminary biography, flyers, writing, and ephemera related to his Getty Research Institute Fellowship in 2006-2007; a J. Paul Getty Trust oral history transcript about his time as a Scholar in Residence and Senior Advisor at the J. Paul Getty Trust; and material related to his membership of the Pacific Council on International Policy (PCIP) including correspondence about work he did as a Senior Fellow for Religion and International Relations, notes, research and reference material, a book plan, background and policies of the organization, memos, reports, proposals for a guest lecture series, and information related to events.
  - Getty Research Institute 06-07 fellowship, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Pacific Council on International Policy (PCIP) people resources (?), 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pacific Council on International Policy (PCIP) book plan, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Pacific Council on International Policy (PCIP) background and policies, 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Pacific Council on International Policy (PCIP) memos, guest lists, events, 2001-2004 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Pacific Council on International Policy (PCIP), 1997-2001 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Rockefeller, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Pacific Council on International Policy (PCIP) personal correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Pacific Council on International Policy (PCIP) - Rockefeller Bros. series, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Future PCIP/Pew Invitations, 2005-2006 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - J. Paul Getty Trust Oral History Project, 2009-2011 (Box 12, Folder 45-47)
  - Fellowship letter from John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Biographical, 1950-2021; 1904-2021; Series 6.
  This series consists of biographical and personal material related to Jack Miles. Material includes digital photographs of Miles and family members through the years and digital descendants/pedigree charts (see Additional Collection Guides for access); school and early life memorabilia such as a Youth Achievement Award from St. Ignatius College Preparatory School; photographs of Miles as editor of his high school newspaper, "Spirit", with copies of the newspaper; a laminated newspaper article about him entering seminary; school transcripts; scholarship information and confirmation documents; awards and certificates through the years; biographical statements and curriculum vitae; poetry for family members; a booklet from the State of the Union Address to the 104th Congress signed to Miles by President Bill Clinton; and real estate and landlording documents.
  - Certificates, 1966, 1971 (Box FB-020, Folder 10)
  - HOC class of 1956 directory, Our Lady Help of Christians School, Chicago, Illinois, 2006 September (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Website, CV, and Contemporary Authors entry, circa 2017 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Curriculum Vitae, circa 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - State of the Union Address to the 104th Congress booklet signed by Bill Clinton, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Observing, 2001 October 7 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - October 15, 1966, 1991 October 15 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Expecting, 1985 September 23 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Various personal materials, 1995-2021, undated (Box 9, Folder 7-11)
  - Degree of Doctor of Humane Letters, honoris causa from Hebrew Union College - Jewish Institute of Religion, 2009-2010 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Degree of Doctor of Humane Letters, honoris causa from American Jewish University, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Muslim Ummah of North America (MUNA) Award for a Special Friend of the Bangladeshi and Muslim Communities, 2011 October (Box 9, Folder 17, Box 16)
  - University of California Academic Senate, Irvine Division Distinguished Faculty Award for Research, 2016-2017 (Box 16)
  - Los Angeles Times Pulitzer Prize - Spot News 1992 Los Angeles Riots award (Box 16)
  - Medal, 1969 (Box 17)
  - Chicago Daily News Youth Achievement Award, St. Ignatius High School, 1960 (Box 18)
  - MacArthur Fellow for the period 2002-2007, 2017 March 14 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Degree of Doctor of Humane Letters, honoris causa from Meadville Theological School of Lombard College, 2007 June 3 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - CalTech Associated Students of the California Institute of Technology (ASCIT) teaching award, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Real estate and landlording miscellany, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - High school records, circa 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - School memorabilia, 1956-1960 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Diplomas and awards, 1960-1996 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper clipping about first writing job, circa 1959 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Certificate of Confirmation, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - School transcripts, 1956-1966 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Sub-lease agreement with Philip Roth, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Remembrance of first Holy Communion booklet, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Rhyming Charm for a Happy Home to Come, 2021 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Early life, school materials, and photographs, 1957, 1962, undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Selective service (draft) registration and classification, 1960, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Unprocessed digital media, 1964-1966, 1990s (Box 20)
    Includes recordings on CDs from the 1960s, floppy disks, and flash drives.
- Writings and correspondence, 2019-2022
  This accession contains materials relating to Jack Miles' 2022 book 'A Friendship in Twilight: Lockdown Conversations on Death and Life' co authored by Mark C. Taylor, correspondence with fellow writers, shorter publications, and articles that shaped the authors discussions.
  - Plague Diaries letters, 2020
    This accession contains materials relating to Jack Miles' 2022 book 'A Friendship in Twilight: Lockdown Conversations on Death and Life' co authored by Mark C. Taylor. The book contains a one quarter to one third of the email letters written by Miles and Taylor from March 15 to May 14, 2020 and details the pairs thoughts on the Covid-19 Pandemic, racial inequality in US, higher education, the 2020 election, religion, philosophy, family, history, and a host of other topics. This accession is comprised of a selection of letters that were not published in the book.
    - Plague Diaries letters, 2020 (Box 21, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence and shorter publications, 2019-2022
    These correspondence materials pertain to conversations with other writers, such as novelist Viet Thanh Nguyen, as well as copies of Miles' remarks from the 2022 induction of UCI graduates into the Phi Beta Kappa Society on June 9th, 2022 and talk given at "What Matters to Me and Why" series at UCI which was subsequently lightly adapted and published in 'The American Scholar'.
    - Correspondence and shorter publications, 2019-2022 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - Articles and book extras, 2019-2022
    These materials contain articles that Miles and Taylor used to inform and shape their discussions about politics, health, religion, ect. as well as notes pertaining to their book planning process and extra book content.
    - Articles relating to 'A Friendship in Twilight', 2019-2022 (Box 22, Folder 3-5)
    - Plague Diaries extras, 2019-2022 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Lockdown letters, 2020-2022 (Box 23, Folder 3)